Fitchburg, Mass. Calvinistic Congregational Church records, 1805-2006.
Congregational Library & Archives
- Church societies and clubs, 1825 1995; 1825-1995; 87 Files; (39 volumes, 48 folders)
  - United Workers of the Calvinistic Congregational Church, 1891 1957; 1891-1957; 9 Cubic Feet; (8 volumes, 1 folder)
    - United Workers records, 1911 1923; 1911-1923 (Box 4, Volume 3)
    - United Workers receipts and treasurer's reports, 1919 1949; 1919-1949 (Box 7, Volume 1)
    - United Workers records, 1923 1930; 1923-1930 (Box 4, Volume 4)
    - United Workers records, 1930 1937; 1930-1937 (Box 4, Volume 5)
    - United Workers records, 1937 1946; 1937-1946 (Box 4, Volume 6)
    - United Workers records, 1946 1957; 1946-1957 (Box 4, Volume 7)
    - United Workers history and programs, 1928 1934; 1928, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fraternal Brotherhood of the Calvinistic Congregational Church, 1910 1942; 1910-1942; 6 Files; (2 volumes, 4 folders)
    This subseries contains the records of the Men's Club, including record books, event details, the society's constitution, and society communications and correspondence.
    - The Men's Club records, 1910 1936; 1910-1936 (Box 4, Volume 15)
    - The Men's Club records, 1936 1942; 1936-1942 (Box 4, Volume 16)
    - The Men's Club events, 1930 1942; circa 1930-1942 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - The Men's Club constitution and records, 1940 1941; 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - The Men's Club records, 1940 1941; 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Men's Club communications, 1941 1942; 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fitchburg Choral Society, 1911 1930; 1911-1930; 3 Folders
    This subseries contains the programs and concert details produced by the Choral Society.
    - Choral Society programs, 1911 1929; 1911-1917, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Spring Festival programs, 1918 1925; 1918-1925; 6 Items (Box 17)
      The programs for the years 1923 and 1924 are not present in the collection.
    - Concerts, 1922 1930; 1922-1930 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fitchburg Woman's Club, 1919 1945; 1919-1945; 25 Items
    This subseries includes the yearly event calendars produced by the Fitchburg Woman's Club. There are small gaps present in the collection.
    - Calendar of the Fitchburg Woman's Club, 1919 1941; 1919-1941; 21 Items (Box 16)
      The calendar for the years 1930-1931 is not present in the collection.
    - Calendar of the Fitchburg Woman's Club, 1941 1945; 1941-1945; 4 Items (Box 17)
  - Hisanhern Club of the Calvinistic Congregational Church, 1941 1995; 1941-1995; 1 Folder
    This subseries contains the record book of the Hisanhern Club, a church singles club.
    - Hisanhern Club records, 1941 1995; 1941-1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Woman's Guild of the Calvinistic Congregational Church, 1953 1970; 1953-1970; 8 Files; (2 volumes, 6 folders)
    This subseries contains the records of the Woman's Guild of the C. C. Church, including record books, event calendars, correspondence, the society's constitution, member lists, and personnel files.
    - Woman's Guild calendars, 1953-1967; 15 Items (Box 17)
    - Woman's Guild records, 1957 1968; 1957-1968 (Box 4, Volume 13)
    - Woman's Guild records, 1969 1971; 1969-1971 (Box 4, Volume 14)
    - Woman's Guild communications, 1959 1967; 1959-1967 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Woman's Guild events and clippings, 1960 1969; 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Woman's Guild constitution, members, and officers, undated, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Woman's Guild charitable works, 1961 1970; 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Jilian S. Himes resume, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Aims, Ambitions, Ideals Service Club of the Calvinistic Congregational Church, 1953 1970; 1953-1970; 3 Folders
    This subseries contains the records, event calendars, and by-laws of the A.A.I Service Club of the C. C. Church.
    - A.A.I Service Club records, 1953 1958; 1953-1958 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - A.A.I. Service Club calendars, 1954 1970; 1954-1970; 24 Items (Box 17)
    - By-Laws and presidents of the A.A.I. Service Club, 1957 1962; 1957-1962 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Junior Pilgrim Youth Fellowship, 1954 1966; 1954-1966; 2 Files; (1 volume, 1 folder)
    This subseries contains the record book and financial records of the Junior Pilgrim Youth Fellowship program.
    - Junior Pilgrim Youth Fellowship treasurer's book, 1954 1959; 1954-1959 (Box 5, Volume 5)
    - Junior Pilgrim Youth Fellowship records, 1961 1966; 1961-1966 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - COMETS, 1976 1995; 1976-1995; 4 Folders
    This subseries contains the record books of COMETS, a joint Congregational and Methodist club formed after the formation of the Faith United Parish.
    - COMETS records, 1976 1979; 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - COMETS records, 1980 1985; 1980-1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - COMETS records, 1986 1990; 1986-1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - COMETS records, 1991 1995; 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Calendars and bulletins, 1887 1972; 1887-1972; 42 Folders
  This series contains published bulletins, magazines, event calendars, and weekly worship programs for the Calvinistic Congregational Church.
  - The Parish Visitor, 1887 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous calendars, 1888 1919; 1888-1919 (Box 8)
  - Lend-A-Hand, 1889 1891; 1889-1891 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Church calendar, 1917 1918; 1917-1918 (Box 8)
  - Church calendar, 1918 1919; 1918-1919 (Box 8)
  - Church calendar, 1919 1920; 1919-1920 (Box 8)
  - Calvinistic Chimes, 1918 1920; 1918-1920 (Box 9)
  - Church bulletin, 1921 1922; 1921-1922 (Box 8)
  - Church bulletin, 1922 1923; 1922-1923 (Box 8)
  - Church bulletin, 1923 1924; 1923-1924 (Box 8)
  - Church bulletin, 1926 (Box 8)
  - The Beacon vol. 1, 1926 (Box 8)
  - The Beacon vol. 4, 1929 (Box 8)
  - The Beacon vol. 5, 1929 1930; 1929-1930 (Box 8)
  - The Beacon vol. 6, 1930 1931; 1930-1931 (Box 8)
  - The Beacon vol. 7, 1931 1932; 1931-1932 (Box 8)
  - Services of Re-opening, 1935 (Box 8)
  - The Beacon vol. 14, 1938 1939; 1938-1939 (Box 8)
  - The Beacon vol. 15, 1939 1940; 1939-1940 (Box 8)
  - The Beacon vol. 16, 1940 1941; 1940-1941 (Box 9)
  - The Beacon vol. 17, 1941 1942; 1941-1942 (Box 9)
  - The Beacon vol. 18, 1942 1943; 1942-1943 (Box 9)
  - The Beacon vol. 19, 1943 1944; 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - The Beacon vol. 20, 1944 1945; 1944-1945 (Box 9)
  - The Beacon vol. 23, 1947 1948; 1947-1948 (Box 9)
  - The Beacon vol. 29, 1954 1955; 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - The Beacon vol. 34, 1959 1960; 1959-1960 (Box 10)
  - The Beacon vol. 35, 1960 1961; 1960-1961 (Box 10)
  - The Beacon vol. 36, 1961 1962; 1961-1962 (Box 10)
  - The Beacon vol. 37, 1962 1963; 1962-1963 (Box 11)
  - The Beacon vol. 38, 1963 1964; 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - The Beacon vol. 39, 1964 1965; 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - The Sunday Bulletin, 1967 1968; 1967-1968 (Box 12)
  - The Sunday Bulletin, 1968 1969; 1968-1969 (Box 13)
  - The Sunday Bulletin, 1969 1970; 1969-1970 (Box 13)
  - The Sunday Bulletin, 1970 1971; 1970-1971 (Box 14)
  - Attendance Records, 1959 1969; 1959-1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Separated Materials
    These attendence records were originally attatched to the weekly bulletins, but became detached and orphaned before the collection's accession.
  - The Weekly Reminder vol. 2, 1967 1968; 1967-1968 (Box 14)
  - The Weekly Reminder / The Mission vol. 3, 1968 1969; 1968-1969 (Box 14)
  - The Mission / The Mission News vol. 4, 1969 1970; 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - The Mission News vol. 5, 1970 1971; 1970-1971 (Box 15)
  - The Mission News vol. 6, 1971 1972; 1971-1972 (Box 15)
- Graphic materials, 1914 1980; circa 1914-1980; 12 Folders
  This series contains graphic materials related to the Calvinistic Congregational Church. The mediums covered include photographs, slide negatives, print negatives, and lithographs. Subject matters covered include portraits, photographs of gatherings, and photographic materials related to the restoration of the church.
  - Altrurian class photograph, 1914 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Altrurian Club photograph, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - C. C. Junior Choir photograph, 1957 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Final Altrurian gathering photograph, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Rose window, Faith United Parish, negative, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Rose window, Faith United Parish, negative, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Faith united Parish, "United Through Grace," restoration photographs, undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Faith united Parish, "United Through Grace," restoration slides, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Church face lithographs, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Family photograph, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - C.C. Church S.P.Y.F. mens sports team photograph, undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Jean Pearson and Rev. Dr. Russell A. Murphy, "Overseas Bound", undated (Box 23, Folder 11)